Gabriele Medeot

(+44) 07762246782 ghaelen.m@gmail.com

I am a Machine Learning Researcher and Software Engineer specialising in deep learning and generative models. I am able to build machine learning models extremely rapidly, and move them swiftly from prototype to production. I'm a fast learner and acquire new knowledge easily. I am also a musician, playing wind instruments: clarinet, saxophone and flute.

SELECTED WORKING EXPERIENCE

TikTok (Bytedance), London (UK) — *Senior Machine Learning Researcher*

APRIL 2019 - PRESENT

Top unicorn startup TikTok is revolutionising content creation and consumption through the use of Artificial Intelligence. I am currently part of the London SAMI team where I contribute to state-of-the-art Machine Learning research, with a focus on speech, audio and music intelligence. I also supervise groups of up to 5 people for particular projects.

Jukedeck, London (UK) — Machine Learning Researcher

APRIL 2015 - APRIL 2019

At Jukedeck we did cutting edge research in the field of music generation with deep learning. The startup has been featured in BBC, The Financial Times, The New York Times, Wired and Forbes and won prizes like Techcrunch, Le Web, and the Cannes Lions innovation award. I brought machine learning to Jukedeck in 2015, and since then helped to build the team.. At Jukedeck I developed machine learning prototypes, researched new models and also managed a junior researcher.

Smartlab University of Trieste, Trieste (IT) — *Internship*

OCTOBER 2011 - APRIL 2012

At SmartLab at the University of Trieste I worked on installing laser and ultrasound sensors on a self driving wheeled robot.

EDUCATION

La Sapienza University, Rome (IT) — *Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics* October 2012 - APRIL 2015 - GRADE 110/100

I learnt to design and implement artificial intelligence and robotic systems, as well as the interdisciplinary skills that are essential to managing complex projects and their impact on the society.

University of Trieste, Trieste (IT) — *Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering* October 2007 - APRIL 2012

I learnt all the skills required to design software in most programming languages as well as manage complex projects from beginning to end.

Conservatory of Trieste, Trieste (IT) — *Bachelor's Degree in Clarinet Performance* JULY 2010

Here I studied clarinet performance to professional level, and acquired the skills needed to play clarinet in orchestra and chamber music ensembles and teach music theory and clarinet performance.

SKILLS

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Reinforcement Learning

Generative Models

Recurrent Models

Team management

CODING

Python,

Tensorflow, Theano, Pytorch, Keras

flask

Matlab, octave

Java, c++

HTML, PHP, CSS

Javascript

swift

LANGUAGES

Italian

Mother Tongue

English

Full Working Proficiency

Spanish

Limited Working

Proficiency

PUBLICATIONS

StrucutureNet: Inducing Structure in Generated Melodies

The International Society of Music Information Retrieval Conference 2018 [PDF]

Automated midi music composition server

Patent Office: US 2020 [PDF]

A deep learning method for enforcing coherence in Automatic Chord Recognition

The International Society of Music Information Retrieval Conference 2021 [PDF]

A method of generating music data

Patent Office: US 2021 [PDF]

A deep learning method for melody extraction from a polyphonic symbolic music representation

The International Society of Music Information Retrieval Conference 2022 [PDF]